Mystify: Michael Hutchence is a documentary, music
film directed by Richard Lowenstein.
Michael Hutchence was flying high as the lead singer of the
legendary rock band INXS until his untimely death in 1997.
Richard Lowenstein’s documentary examines Hutchence’s deeply
felt life through his many loves and demons.
Self (archive footage), played by Michael Hutchence.
Self, played by Kylie Minogue.
Self, played by Helena Christensen.
Self, played by Bono.
Self (archive footage), played by Noel Gallagher.
Self, played by Michele Bennett.
Mystify: Michael Hutchence is a 2019 documentary film about the life of musician, actor and
singer-songwriter Michael Hutchence, lead vocalist of the Australian rock band INXS.
It is written and directed by Richard Lowenstein and relies primarily on rare archive footage, outtakes, private home
video and audio commentary provided by friends, ex-partners, band members, record producers and family.
An Australian-British venture, the film was co-produced by Ghost Pictures, Passion
Pictures with Madman Entertainment and Dogwoof serving as distributors.
It is in association with Baird Films and Film Victoria.
Mystify: Michael Hutchence had its world premiere at the Tribeca Film Festival on 25
April 2019, and was theatrically released in Australia on 4 July 2019.
The film was released in the United Kingdom on 18 October
receiving generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of depression, suicide, rock
star, home video, archive footage.
The tone is thought_provoking.